The Pastry of Knowledge.
“智慧甜品”
It's one of Eden Academy's seven wonders, which is whispered among the students.
在学生们之间秘密地流传 伊甸学园七大不可思议之一
A mysterious pastry chef randomly appears in the cafeteria out of nowhere
学生餐厅里出现了一个 不知道从哪里来的甜点师傅
and serves exquisite desserts
有时会随性做出
on a whim.
美味至极的甜点
Many of those who ate it,
很多吃过那道甜点的学生
later became Imperial Scholars.
后来就成为了皇帝的学生
Therefore a rumor spread
因此就出现了谣言
that eating his desserts will make one smarter in an instant.
说是吃了他的甜点 会马上变得更聪明
A group of students at Eden are still vying for a chance to order his dessert.
伊甸里有一群学生 虎视眈眈等着要吃他做的甜点
ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
(远藤达哉原创作品 连载于集英社漫画杂志《SHONEN JUMP PLUS》)
MISSION:29 PART A: THE PASTRY OF KNOWLEDGE
剧名:任务:29 A Part:智慧甜品
Are you, by any chance,
难道你是...
the prince I met the other day?
我那天遇到的王子吗?
No, I'm just your clone.
不是 我是你的分身
No, I know what I'm seeing. Your eyes, and hair...
不会有错的 你的眼睛还有头发...
Yes, you're my prince! I love you!
是我的王子!我喜欢你!
No, I'm just another female sheep just like you.
不是 我跟你一样是只母绵羊
Oh come on! This story is going nowhere!
拜托你好不好! 这样故事就发展不下去了!
- The story's a mess! - But they look identical.
-乱七八糟的! -可是它们长的一模一样啊
Just ignore that part for the sake of the story.
从故事设定上来看 这点要忽略掉
It's my turn next.
轮到阿尼亚了
It'll be a battle between twins separated at birth.
故事是有关于 出生就被分开的双胞胎之间的战斗
No way! A battle will end up damaging them!
不要 战斗的话 这两只娃娃会受伤的
By the way, have you heard?
对了 你听说了吗?
At the end of the term, we'll be divided into classes by academic ability.
下一学期开始要用学力分班了
What do you mean?
什么意思?
Basically, someone like me who has decent grades
简单来说 像我这样成绩优良的学生
and someone like you who's not doing so well,
跟像你这样成绩低下的学生
will end up in separate classes for certain subjects.
有些科目要分开上课了
LABORIOUS CLASS - OTHER
(中段班、后段班)
I'll be all alone!
那阿尼亚就只剩一个人了!
That's right. So you have to make sure you study harder.
没错 所以你要更加用功才行
In addition to the midterms and finals,
除了期中考试跟期末考试
I hear that tomorrow's quiz will also be taken into consideration.
听说明天的小考也会纳入分班考量
The test on classical language will be one of them!
古语考试也是其中一项!
This is not good!
大事不妙了!
It's all over for me now.
阿尼亚完蛋了
- Did you hear? It appeared! - What?
-大事不妙 出现了! -什么东西?怎么了?
That rumored dessert is available at Dining Hall Two!
传说的甜点出现在第二食堂了!
- What are you talking about? - You idiot! You don't know?
-你在说什么? -笨蛋 你不知道吗?
It's the dessert made by the legendary former royal pastry chef!
传奇的前任皇家 甜点师傅做的甜点啊!
The Pastry of Knowledge!
智慧甜点!
It's the phantom dessert that makes anyone who eats it an Imperial Scholar!
那可是梦幻甜点 谁吃了就能当上皇帝的学生!
This year, it's macarons.
今年是马卡龙
The supply is limited, so let's hurry before they're all gone!
数量有限 在被买完之前 我们赶快去抢!
If I eat that, I can be a genius too!
吃了那个 阿尼亚也能变天才!
It sounds too good to be true,
听起来就好到不像真的
but it doesn't hurt to rely a little on luck! Not only that...
但是讨个好兆头 也没什么不好!更何况...
macarons made by a former royal chef!
那是前皇家厨师做的马卡龙!
- I want a taste! They'll be delicious! - What's a macaron?
-我想尝尝看!一定很好吃! -什么是马卡龙?
There it is! We have to hurry, or they'll run out!
就是那里!快点 不然就卖光了!
- Second son! - Shorty!
-次子! -小短腿!
- Why are you so desperate?! - Shut up! You're just as desperate!
-你们跑那么急干嘛? -吵死了!你们不是也一样?
There's only one left of Pierre Pommier's newest dessert.
皮耶尔·波米叶的新甜点只剩一份
It's first come first serve.
先抢先赢
I won't let you guys have it!
才不要让给你们呢!
This is a battle with a Stella Star on the line!
这可是星星争夺战!
- I'll take one please. - Sure thing.
-请给我一份 -没问题
We're all sold out today.
今天营业时间就到此结束了
Wow, I'm in luck!
好幸运哦!
I wonder if I can get a Stella Star now! I'm so excited!
我是不是也可以拿到星呢? 好期待哦!
- George. - What?
-乔治 -干嘛?
You little jerk, that's mine!
你这家伙 那是我的!
Give that to me! I was planning to eat that!
把它给我!我本来打算要吃的!
This is robbery!
你们这是抢劫!
I bought this with what little money I have! I'm not giving it away!
这是我用身上仅有的钱买的 我才不要给别人!
Hey! I never got my pencil case back from you!
喂 你还没还我铅笔盒!
And I ended up having to sing for you! It was embarrassing.
我也被你骗去唱歌耶! 很丢脸好不好!
I gave you a leaf.
我给了你一片叶子
Fine then. There's five macarons
那好吧 总共有五个马卡龙
so you guys can take four of them, and let's call it even, okay?
那你们可以拿四个 这样就扯平了吧?
You're not so bad after all.
你真是个好人
There are four left.
剩下四个
And thus,
因此
it was the beginning of a fierce battle to become the next Imperial Scholar.
为了当上下届皇帝的学生 激烈的争斗就此拉开序幕
One game of Old Maid.
玩一局抽鬼牌
The player in last-place won't get the macaron.
最后一名就不能吃马卡龙
Sure. Bring it on.
好啊 放马过来吧
I've never played cards before. I don't know the rules.
我从来没玩过牌 不知道游戏规则
- Is she serious? - It's simple.
-真的假的? -规则很简单
Pair up the cards with the same number, while avoiding the joker card.
避开鬼牌的同时 要把相同数字的牌组成一对
Got it.
懂了
Let's begin.
开始吧
Pass the joker.
把鬼牌传过来
- Make her take it, so that she'll lose! - Roger!
-然后让她拿走 那她就输了! -收到!
The Pastry of Knowledge would be wasted on someone who can't play the Old Maid.
把智慧甜点给不会玩抽鬼牌的人 根本就是浪费
Hey, it's your turn to draw a card.
轮到你抽牌了
Right now, I have a six, four, ten, and...
阿尼亚有一张六 一张四、一张十 还有...
You don't have to reveal your cards, Anya.
不用讲出来啦 阿尼亚
What an idiot.
真笨
I'll make the joker stand out, and hide the six a little.
把鬼牌推出去一点 然后把六稍微收进来一点
Go on and pick a card.
来选牌吧
Six!
六!
Impressive, Anya!
好厉害哦 阿尼亚!
That was a coincidence.
那是刚好而已
Four! Ten! A! Old man!
- 四!十! - A!大叔!
I did it! I don't have any more cards left!
太好了 阿尼亚牌都出光了!
Hold on! Why are you so good at this?
等等 你怎么那么会玩?
That's right! You cheated! You must have marked the cards!
没错 你作弊啦! 你一定在牌上做了记号!
Hey, stop accusing her like that.
什么啊 不要这样诬赖人
If she didn't cheat, the only explanation left is that she can read minds!
她要是没作弊 唯一能解释的理由就是她会读心!
Oh crap! I got a little carried away!
糟了 阿尼亚太得意忘形了!
If you're going to be so adamant, let's do another round.
你们要是不甘心的话 也可以再玩一次
What? You're too soft.
什么?你也太好说话了
Let's play with a brand-new deck! We'll switch up the order too!
用新的扑克牌再玩一次! 顺序也要换过!
- Don't you dare cheat anymore! - I wasn't.
-你不准再作弊了! -我才没有
That was close.
好险哦
I have to make mistakes on purpose
我必须故意失败才行
so that they don't find out that I'm a telepath.
这样他们才不会发现我有超能力
The joker came to me.
鬼牌跑到我这里来了
Your turn.
到你了
- The joker is in the middle. Pick that! - I have to make a mistake on purpose.
-鬼牌在中间 快抽那张! -我必须故意失败
Oh no. I made a mistake and picked the joker.
糟了 我失误了 居然抽中鬼牌
- You're so lame! - How stupid! So dumb!
-好逊哦! -真笨!大傻瓜!
This is time to use my...
是时候用我的必杀...
Anya, you can't punch them.
阿尼亚 你不可以揍他们
I wasn't lucky this time.
我这次运气不好
That was close. If I get expelled the mission will fail.
真是好险 被退学的话 任务就会失败了
I need to be a cool liar, like Father.
阿尼亚要变成像父亲那样酷酷的骗子
It's no big deal. I'll be all right as long as I make him pick
没什么大不了的 只要让他抽走鬼牌
the joker.
阿尼亚就没事了
Pick a card.
你选一张
She's so easy to read.
这家伙还真好懂
All right. I got a pair.
好了 我有一对了
Wait, don't tell me... Can he read minds too?
难道说次子也会读心吗?
- I'm out! - Me too!
-脱手! -我也是!
Oh crap! I still have the joker!
惨了 鬼牌还在阿尼亚这里!
I'm out too!
我也脱手了!
- Damian, you're not good at this, huh? - Shut up!
-达米安同学其实也不太会玩吧? -少啰嗦!
You can do it, Anya!
加油 阿尼亚!
I can do this!
我可以的!
This will decide the game.
这一抽就定胜负了
I can win as long as I look at the expression on her face!
只要看她的表情 我一定会赢!
I have to deceive him and make him pick the joker!
必须骗他选走鬼牌才行!
If I lose, I can't eat that dessert, and I'll be as dumb as ever.
输了的话就吃不到甜点 阿尼亚就会继续当笨蛋
Then I'll fail the test, and I won't be in the same class as Becky!
然后考试也考不好 还要跟贝姬分开上课!
I'll be all alone!
阿尼亚就会只剩自己一个了!
All right! This one is not the joker!
很好 这张不是鬼牌
Here's four macarons.
给你们四个马卡龙
Hooray! They look delicious!
好耶!看起来好好吃哦!
How exciting!
好兴奋!
Why in the world did you pick the joker at the very end, Damian?
达米安大人 你最后怎么会挑中鬼牌呢?
Shut up!
吵死了!
That was a dirty move, dammit!
那家伙真狡猾 可恶!
Hey,
次子
wanna split this?
要不要一人一半?
I don't want it, you idiot!
我...我才不要咧 笨蛋!
I can become an Imperial Scholar without eating something like that!
就是不吃那种东西 我也可以当上皇帝的学生!
An idiot should eat that! idiot!
笨蛋才需要吃那个!笨蛋!
- Unbelievable. - He's so rude!
-切! -真没礼貌!
Let's eat, Anya!
我们来吃吧 阿尼亚
Let's enjoy it!
我开动了!
- It's delicious! - Now I can get a Stella Star too!
-好好吃! -现在我也可以拿到星了!
Begin your quiz.
考试开始
That's it. I'm going to be all alone.
完蛋了 我要孤零零一个人了
My future here at school is looking bleak.
阿尼亚的学途一片黑暗
That's not true! Let's work hard on the finals!
没那种事啦 期末考一起加油吧!
Yeah. You're better off than me who's already all alone.
对啊 你至少比 已经孤零零的我好多了
Wow, these school tests are pretty hard, huh?
学校的考试真的很难耶
I'm going to sulk for a bit.
阿尼亚要去生闷气一下
Her academic skills have improved a little,
她的学力稍微有点长进
but there's a long road ahead of us.
不过前途依旧漫漫啊
This classical language test...
这份古语考卷...
Points were docked for misspellings,
几乎都是因为拼错被扣分
but she would've scored high if it wasn't for that.
不然的话分数会很高的
She hasn't studied much classical language yet.
她应该还没有学到那么多古语才对
Did she learn it in the environment of her upbringing?
是在原本的出生环境下 耳濡目染学的吗?
But there are no countries that still use that language.
但目前已经没有国家在使用古语
No, there's no point in delving into her past.
不 再追究她的过去也没有意义
Hey Anya, I made Salisbury steak for dinner.
阿尼亚 晚饭给你做汉堡排哦
Salisbury steak!
汉堡排!
I tried my hand at making dessert!
我也试着做了甜点哦!
This is the fake ID for Department Two of Doust Industries.
这是达斯特工业 第二作业区的伪造识别证
And this is the engine test results for a new fighter jet.
这一份则是 新型战斗机的引擎测试数据
MISSION:29 - PART B: THE INFORMANT'S GREAT ROMANCE PLAN II
剧名:任务:29 B Part: 情报商的恋爱大作战II
Thanks for your help.
一直以来多亏有你帮忙了
Well, it's not for free.
这可不是免费情报哦
What about the pictures of the members of the association I asked for?
之前拜托你找的协会成员相片呢?
Oh that. Give me some more time.
那个啊 再给我一点时间
One informant who specialized in that was recently eliminated.
有个专门 干那行的情报商最近被做掉了
- State Security Service? - No.
-安全部吗? -不是
I don't know for sure, but rumor says that he was eliminated by The Garden.
我还不是太确定 但传闻说是“花园”的人做掉他的
Garden? The group of assassins that's been operating in this country since long ago?
“花园”?据说是这个国家 很久以前就有的暗杀组织?
They're an urban legend, aren't they?
他们不是都市传说吗?
No, they definitely exist.
不是 他们是真的存在
They've been purging traitors under the orders of the shadow government.
他们一直以来 都听令于地下政府 负责追杀卖国贼
Well, it's no surprise that there's an unofficial paramilitary organization.
有这种非官方的 民兵组织存在也不奇怪
They're nothing that soft, you idiot!
笨蛋 他们可没那么好对付!
They're so strong that one soldier can wipe out an entire military troop!
他们一名士兵就有 歼灭一个军队的力量!
Stop being ridiculous and fulfill my request.
别胡说八道了 赶快完成我的委托
Wait. In exchange for all the extra work, help me with my job.
慢着 作为我额外工作的回报 你也帮我工作吧
A job?
工作?
LOST
(走失)
- This cat. - A lost cat?
-这只猫 -猫咪走失?
This is Kopi who belongs to a server named Kacey, who works at my favorite café.
它叫柯比 是我最爱的咖啡厅里 一个叫凯西的服务生养的猫
He's been lost since last week,
它上星期就不见了
and Kacey is devastated.
凯西为此非常伤心
Twilight, in order to make Kacey smile once again,
黄昏 为了让凯西重拾笑容
and to increase my chances with her,
以及让我跟她之间有发展感情的机会
help me find this cat!
帮我找到这只猫吧!
Hey! Stop right there!
喂 你给我站住!
I won't give you intel, if you won't help me!
你不帮我 我就不给你情报哦!
Hey!
喂!
I'll even add in the newly invented toothbrush-shaped pistol.
我另外送你新研发的牙刷型手枪
Dammit! He's so cold-hearted!
可恶 真是没血没泪的家伙!
Fine then. I'll find that cat all on my own!
那好吧 我就自己去找猫!
Don't underestimate an informant!
少瞧不起情报商了!
Hey, Jeffrey.
喂 杰弗里
That's right. It's a job. I'm looking for a cat.
没错 有工作 我在找一只猫
A male Nortblue with a bell around his neck.
是只诺尔特蓝猫 公的 脖子上挂着铃铛
Let me know if you find him. Thanks.
找到了就跟我说一声 谢了
It's been a while, Hound Joe!
好久不见了 猎犬老乔!
I need to rely on your skills for a job.
有件事需要靠你的能力
Hello, Terrence!
喂 特伦斯!
Yes, it's an emergency.
对 是急事!
Hey, Nancy!
喂 南西!
You know a lot about cats, huh?
你对猫很了解吧?
Connect me to Harrison at Branch Office 22.
请帮我转接给第22分局的哈里逊
Hello, Mr. Jasper!
你好啊 贾斯帕!
Hey, Pat!
喂 帕特啊!
Spotted a cat matching that description on Ritter Street near the city hall.
我在市政厅附近的瑞特尔街看到猫了
Nice work, Joe!
干得好 老乔!
It should be around here somewhere.
应该就在这一带了
- Oh, Franky, is that you? - Huh?
-这不是弗兰克先生吗? -咦?
- Yor? - Hello!
-约尔小姐? -你好!
Hello.
你好
Oh yeah, you work at the city hall, huh?
对哦 你在市政厅工作吧?
Yes. I'm about to take my lunch break.
对啊 我正要去午休
Do you work around here too, Franky?
弗兰克先生 你在这附近工作吗?
No, the thing is...
不是啦 是这样的...
A lost cat? How sad!
猫咪走失了?真糟糕!
I'll help you.
我也来帮你吧
What? But you're about to go on your lunch break.
什么?你不是要去午休吗?
No worries. After all, you're...
没关系 毕竟你是...
my husband's... friend who is in need of help!
我丈夫的朋友...你需要帮忙嘛!
She's still playing the role of a wife pretty seriously, huh?
她很认真在扮演太太的角色呢
Of course, I'll only do it if you don't mind...
当然 如果这样 不会造成你困扰的话...
- Then, I appreciate your help. - Of course!
-那就拜托你了 -没问题!
Which way did Kopi go?
柯比先生往哪里去了?
I just know that he's somewhere near here.
我刚刚得知它在这附近
I planted C-20,
我已经在这一带
the Feline-form Listening Device in areas where cats gather together.
猫咪聚集的地方 装了猫型窃听器C20
It's installed with sensors that'll react to the sound of the bell on Kopi's collar.
上面配置了传感器 只要听到柯比的铃铛声就会有反应
Franky, you're so amazing!
弗兰克先生 你好厉害哦!
Leave it up to me!
包在我身上!
The C-20 at Point A is being attacked!
A点的C20被攻击了!
Oh no!
糟了!
No way! It was destroyed!
不是吧 被破坏掉了!
What about the other ones?
其他地点的呢?
They were eliminated because they were seen as intruders.
猫咪把它当成侵入者歼灭了
This strategy has failed.
这个策略失败了
It's tough out there in the world of cats, huh?
猫咪的世界也不好混呢
Then I will maneuver things to lure the cats to us!
既然如此 我就用诱饵 引诱猫咪来找我们吧!
CAT-NIP, the Cat Nearness Inducement Prototype Decoy System!
木天蓼 猫咪诱饵原型系统!
This releases the scent of catnip to lure the cats to us.
这个装置会散发出木天蓼的香气 引诱猫咪来找我们
Wow, Franky, you're so talented!
弗兰克先生 你好有才华哦!
Are you a craftsman?
你是工匠吗?
I'm just a boy who always dreamed of making the world a better place
我只是一心梦想着 用我的发明让世界变得更好
with my inventions and perhaps getting rich from patents.
最好还可以靠专利变有钱的年轻人
How lovely!
好棒哦!
I can't tell her what I really do.
我不能告诉她我的真实职业
Whoa!
哇!
Oh my.
哎呀
Oh no! There's too many of them!
惨了 也太多猫了!
Which one of them is Kopi?
哪一只是柯比先生?
- There it is! The gray one! - What? Which one?
-在那里!灰色那只! -什么?哪一只?
I'll get him no matter what!
无论如何我都要抓到你!
Hyper Long Hand! Catch him!
无敌霹雳长长手!抓住他!
I can't do a pinpoint attack! I need a broader approach!
点对点攻击没用! 我需要攻击范围更大的那种!
Hey, don't get inside! Camera-shaped Net Launcher!
喂 别跳进来!相机型捕捉网!
I hear he's really cautious.
听说它戒心很强
I'm going to pretend I'm only taking a picture.
我得假装自己只是要拍张照
I have to be careful here.
必须要谨慎点
But since it's disguised as a camera, this launcher doesn't have a good range.
但因为伪装成相机的关系 能发射的距离有限
I have to get within two meters to catch him!
必须进到两米的范围才能捉住它!
- Stop right there! - That must be Kopi!
-给我站住! -那一定是柯比先生吧!
Kopi, you made me mad!
柯比 你惹毛我了!
There's nothing you can do to fix that now!
后悔也来不及了!
This is the ultimate weapon that took me ten years to develop!
这可是我花了十年开发的终极武器!
It's my exoskeleton power suit that will give me
这套外骨骼套装将会给我
phenomenal physical abilities! Or at least it should...
惊人的超强体能!至少啦...
Just you wait! After I turn on the power, it takes 15 minutes
你给我等着! 启动之后只要十五分钟
for the battery to warm up the motor. Sit tight!
发动机就能完成暖机 你乖乖啊!
What? You idiot! That's a big street up ahead! It's dangerous!
什么?笨蛋! 前面有一条大街 很危险!
Stop! Sorry, I promise I won't chase you anymore!
站住 对不起! 我保证不会再追着你跑了!
Franky, I'm going to borrow this for a little bit.
弗兰克先生 这个稍微借我一下
I caught him!
我抓到了!
I caught him, Franky!
我抓到它了 弗兰克先生!
Oh, yeah. Th... thanks.
哦 是哦...谢谢了
Ten years... ten years of my work.
十年...我的十年之作
You're in luck, Kopi. You can finally go home!
太好了 柯比先生 你终于可以回家了!
But,
不过
this will be all worth it, if it will get Kacey to pay attention to me!
只要凯西能够注意到我 这一切都是值得的!
I'm coming for you, honey!
等着我 甜心!
Thank you so much, Franky!
真是太谢谢你了 弗兰克先生!
Kopi, you really had me worried!
柯比 我真的好担心你!
I'm happy for you, Kacey.
真是太好了 凯西
It's all your fault, Mar, for leaving the front door open!
小马 这都是你的错 还不是因为你没关前门!
I'm sorry.
对不起啦
To make amends, I'll buy you the matching rings you've been wanting.
我会买你一直想要的对戒作为补偿
I'm happy for you... yeah...
真...真是太好了...就是啊...
Well... bye...
那我...告辞了...
Thank you so much, Franky!
真的很谢谢你 弗兰克先生!
I wish you both happiness.
我祝你们俩幸福快乐
The man decided to live only for his work.
男人决定只为工作而活
It sure feels good to help someone out!
果然能帮别人忙 心情就会很好!
It seems like you're in a good mood.
看来前辈心情好像很好呢
Ooh, what could it be? Did your husband buy you something?
怎么了?是先生给你买了东西吗?
No, nothing like that.
不是这样的
Must be nice to have such a happy life.
生活过得那么幸福一定很棒吧
Yeah, how annoying.
就是嘛 真讨厌
Basically, she just became a normal person. That's all.
她只是变成了普通人而已
- Normal? Am I normal? - Huh?
-普通人?我是普通人了? -什么?
I'm so glad.
太好啦
I guess my cover is safe. What a relief.
伪装成功了 我就放心了
Hey Sharon, don't let her get carried away.
莎伦 别让她得意忘形了
I was trying to be sarcastic.
我明明是想讽刺她的
Hey, Briar.
喂 布莱尔
Oh, you're not Briar anymore.
哦 你不叫布莱尔了
- Forger. You have a call. - Yes! Forger. That's me!
-福杰 有你的电话 -对!我姓福杰!
It's from your special customer.
是你负责的特殊客户打来的
Hello. It's me.
喂 电话换我听了
Hello.
你好
You have a new client, Thorn Princess.
你有新客人了 荆棘公主
LUXURY CRUISE
(豪华邮轮)
MISSION:30 PLAN TO CROSS THE BORDER
(任务:30 越境作战)
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻译:洪贞韵